Amen. Well, thank you for that nice introduction, Pastor Pete, and it is nice for me and my family to be visiting Ann Arbor.
This time around, like Pastor Pete mentioned, we lived here for a long time. My wife and I, and it's nice to see some old friends here.
It's nice to see some new friends here as well as get to spend this Sunday with you all.
We definitely appreciate the longstanding friendship
that we've had, but also the partnership in God's mission
as we try to bring the gospel to the nations of the world.
And so you have all been a part of that through your prayers,
through the church's support, through some of you
who are personal partners as well.
And so we're just grateful to be here with you.
We're grateful for you.
And I hope that this time in God's word
ministers to you as well this morning.
We're going to be looking at Psalm 126.
And the title of my sermon today is called Joy
along the journey.
Joy along the journey.
This sermon is a personally written
exposition of Psalm 126.
But it is influenced heavily by a chapter
in Eugene Peterson's book Along Obedience in the same direction.
So this chapter is a meditation on some,
the chapter that I'm referring to is a meditation
on Psalm 126 and God really used Peterson
and this particular chapter to minister to me a lot
in this season of my life.
And so I didn't copy any of his work directly,
but I did recall a lot from memory
as I was writing the sermon.
And so I just wanted to let you know that up front, okay?
One thing that Eugene Peterson points out very keenly
is how we in our current world
use our modern day entertainment to numb ourselves
from various trials and sorrows that we face in life,
difficulties that we face in life.
And so we will pay money to watch a comedy movie
or we'll pay money to watch a stand-up comedian perform and just give us
one or two hours of just some time to laugh and time to forget about what's
going on in in our lives or we'll scroll we'll scroll on social media to find
silly short-form videos that will make us laugh hysterically that we might
want to share with our friends or our family members to make them laugh as
well, but what I would say is that these diversions hardly give us joy. And the joy that I'm talking about
is this lightness of heart despite whatever challenging situations that we face. And I don't mean to
like poo poo on these things. They're not all bad things. They can be good legitimate forms of
recreation when watched in moderation and with discernment. And that's something that I am constantly
trying to assess of growth, the process of character building, the process of
sanctifying that I can testify, have ended in joy in many ways. And in the ways
that it hasn't yet produced joy, I'm trusting that God will end it in joy as
well. And I hope that you too can exercise faith in your life journey because we
know from scripture that God turns our sorrows into joy. So let's pray and I'll close this time
in God's word. God, thank you so much for your word. Forgive us for taking it for granted, but
thank you that you feed us through all these recollections of how you have interceded in history
for people that are broken, messed up, failures, wounded, and we can definitely connect with
that God here.
But we also thank you that we can exercise our faith in Christ who, for the joy, set
for him endured the cross to redeem us ultimately to bring glory to you and so
God we ask and we pray and bring you our sorrows our hardships our pains our
failures we trust you not to make them go away but that you are somehow
working for our good and for your glory to sanctify us, to build us up, to prepare
us. And I pray that that would be the posture of each person here before you
today. I love you, thank you, Jesus' name, amen.